<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reference on Stryke Force Engineering Blog</title>
    <link>https://strykeforce.github.io/categories/reference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reference on Stryke Force Engineering Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 10:40:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://strykeforce.github.io/categories/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Talon SRX Motor Training Course 2017</title>
      <link>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/talon-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 10:40:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/talon-training/</guid>
      <description>Stryke Force hosted students and mentors from West Michigan FRC teams for a Talon SRX motor training on December 9, 2017.
Course Material  Course Presentation with step-by-step closed-loop tuning guide (pdf, pptx) Course Video (coming soon) Grapher and tct utility used for the tuning demonstrations (download information)  Topics  How does a motor work? (turning current into rotary motion) Motor performance (speed/torque curves and what they mean) Talon SRX overview Talon SRX control modes Encoders Configuring an entire axis (Talon SRX + sensor + motor)  Open loop Closed loop -PID Tuning a Closed loop Velocity Position Motion Magic   Questions amd Feedback If you have any questions about this class please ask on Chief Delphi and one of us will be sure to respond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roborio Digital Output</title>
      <link>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/roborio-digital-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 13:32:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/roborio-digital-output/</guid>
      <description>Results from testing the digital outputs on the roboRIO.
Pulse Output The pulse length is set with a double and is passed to the FPGA where it is used to determine the pulse length. Calling DigitalOutput#pulse(double pulseLength) gives the following:
 pulseLength = 0.25: pulse width = 144 µsec pulseLength = 0.50: pulse width = 32 µsec pulseLength = 1.00: pulse width = 64 µsec pulseLength = 2.00: pulse width = 128 µsec pulseLength = 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Setup for 2767</title>
      <link>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/robot-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 11:18:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/robot-ssh/</guid>
      <description>These are instructions for the 2767 team on how to configure easy SSH access to the roboRIO from macOS or Linux. (PuTTY instructions coming&amp;hellip;)
Linux and macOS In the steps below, $ is the command-line prompt and should not be typed when entering commands. Grab a mentor for a walk-through of these instructions if you need help!
 Verify you have a $HOME/.ssh directory and that it has permission of drwx------.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robot Practice Field Network</title>
      <link>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/robot-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 14:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/robot-network/</guid>
      <description>While using FRC radios in the default configuration is easy to set up, having to connect to an isolated robot access point is inconvienient during development when Internet access is required. We have installed OpenWRT on the Open Mesh OM5P-AN used on our robots.
Diagram  Open Mesh OM5P-AN Radio The radio is configured using OpenWRT as a router with its WiFi interface connecting to our shop network with static IP address 192.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>