<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Swerve on Stryke Force Engineering Blog</title>
    <link>https://strykeforce.github.io/tags/swerve/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Swerve on Stryke Force Engineering Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 13:01:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://strykeforce.github.io/tags/swerve/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Third Coast Telemetry with Swerve Drive</title>
      <link>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/thirdcoast-telemetry-swerve/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 13:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/thirdcoast-telemetry-swerve/</guid>
      <description>Using the Third Coast Telemetry Service and Swerve Drive together relies on configuration using Dagger dependency injection. This allows for easy testing and reusable, interchangeable modules. The following code, taken from the example robot in this repository, configures the azimuth and drive Talons for monitoring.
public void robotInit() { try { RobotComponent component; // load config file or create from default resource file in jar  try (FileConfig toml = FileConfig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Coast Swerve Drive</title>
      <link>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/thirdcoast-swerve/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 13:52:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/thirdcoast-swerve/</guid>
      <description>This software is designed to run on swerve drive hardware described in this paper. The swerve drive is controlled using the SwerveDrive class. Derivation of inverse kinematic equations are from Ether&amp;rsquo;s Swerve Kinematics and Programming.
The swerve-drive inverse kinematics algorithm will always calculate individual wheel angles as -0.5 to 0.5 rotations, measured clockwise with zero being the straight-ahead position. Wheel speed is calculated as 0 to 1 in the direction of the wheel angle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Coast Java Library</title>
      <link>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/thirdcoast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 13:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/thirdcoast/</guid>
      <description>The Stryke Force 2767 Third Coast swerve drive, talon configuration and telemetry API source code for FRC robots is available from its repository at https://github.com/strykeforce/thirdcoast.
Documentation Third Coast Javadocs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>