<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talon on Stryke Force Engineering Blog</title>
    <link>https://strykeforce.github.io/tags/talon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talon on Stryke Force Engineering Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 13:48:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://strykeforce.github.io/tags/talon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Coast Java Library</title>
      <link>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/thirdcoast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 13:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/thirdcoast/</guid>
      <description>The Stryke Force 2767 Third Coast swerve drive, talon configuration and telemetry API source code for FRC robots is available from its repository at https://github.com/strykeforce/thirdcoast.
Documentation Third Coast Javadocs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Coast Talon Provisioner</title>
      <link>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/thirdcoast-talon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 06:52:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/thirdcoast-talon/</guid>
      <description>Talon Configurations Note: This library has seen some major changes as a result of the upgrade to CTRE Phoenix Toolkit in 2018.
Third Coast provides a library for storing any number of TalonSRX configurations in a TOML file and applying them to Talons. If this configuration file is not present on the roboRIO in the location you specify, a default configuration file stored in the robot application JAR is used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talon SRX Motor Training Course 2017</title>
      <link>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/talon-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 10:40:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strykeforce.github.io/posts/talon-training/</guid>
      <description>Stryke Force hosted students and mentors from West Michigan FRC teams for a Talon SRX motor training on December 9, 2017.
Course Material  Course Presentation with step-by-step closed-loop tuning guide (pdf, pptx) Course Video (coming soon) Grapher and tct utility used for the tuning demonstrations (download information)  Topics  How does a motor work? (turning current into rotary motion) Motor performance (speed/torque curves and what they mean) Talon SRX overview Talon SRX control modes Encoders Configuring an entire axis (Talon SRX + sensor + motor)  Open loop Closed loop - PID Tuning a Closed loop  Velocity Position Motion Magic    Questions and Feedback If you have any questions about this class please ask on Chief Delphi and one of us will be sure to respond.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>